[
  {
    "question": "llamarse",
    "answer": "heißen"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo me llamo",
    "answer": "ich heiße"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú te llamas",
    "answer": "du heißt"
  },
  {
    "question": "él se llama",
    "answer": "er heißt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella se llama",
    "answer": "sie heißt"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso se llama",
    "answer": "es heißt"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros nos llamamos",
    "answer": "wir heißen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros os llamáis",
    "answer": "ihr heißt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos se llaman",
    "answer": "sie heißen"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted se llama",
    "answer": "Sie heißen"
  },
  {
    "question": "venir",
    "answer": "kommen"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo vengo",
    "answer": "ich komme"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú vienes",
    "answer": "du kommst"
  },
  {
    "question": "él viene",
    "answer": "er kommt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella viene",
    "answer": "sie kommt"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso viene",
    "answer": "es kommt"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros venimos",
    "answer": "wir kommen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros venís",
    "answer": "ihr kommt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos vienen",
    "answer": "sie kommen"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted viene",
    "answer": "Sie kommen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vivir (residir)",
    "answer": "wohnen"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo vivo",
    "answer": "ich wohne"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú vives",
    "answer": "du wohnst"
  },
  {
    "question": "él vive",
    "answer": "er wohnt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella vive",
    "answer": "sie wohnt"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso vive",
    "answer": "es wohnt"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros vivimos",
    "answer": "wir wohnen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros vivís",
    "answer": "ihr wohnt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos viven",
    "answer": "sie wohnen"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted vive",
    "answer": "Sie wohnen"
  },
  {
    "question": "ser / estar",
    "answer": "sein"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo soy / estoy",
    "answer": "ich bin"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú eres / estás",
    "answer": "du bist"
  },
  {
    "question": "él es / está",
    "answer": "er ist"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella es / está",
    "answer": "sie ist"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso es / está",
    "answer": "es ist"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros somos / estamos",
    "answer": "wir sind"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros sois / estáis",
    "answer": "ihr seid"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos son / están",
    "answer": "sie sind"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted es / está",
    "answer": "Sie sind"
  },
  {
    "question": "viajar",
    "answer": "reisen"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo viajo",
    "answer": "ich reise"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú viajas",
    "answer": "du reist"
  },
  {
    "question": "él viaja",
    "answer": "er reist"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella viaja",
    "answer": "sie reist"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso viaja",
    "answer": "es reist"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros viajamos",
    "answer": "wir reisen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros viajáis",
    "answer": "ihr reist"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos viajan",
    "answer": "sie reisen"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted viaja",
    "answer": "Sie reisen"
  },
  {
    "question": "vivir (existir)",
    "answer": "leben"
  },
  {
    "question": "yo vivo",
    "answer": "ich lebe"
  },
  {
    "question": "tú vives",
    "answer": "du lebst"
  },
  {
    "question": "él vive",
    "answer": "er lebt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ella vive",
    "answer": "sie lebt"
  },
  {
    "question": "eso vive",
    "answer": "es lebt"
  },
  {
    "question": "nosotros vivimos",
    "answer": "wir leben"
  },
  {
    "question": "vosotros vivís",
    "answer": "ihr lebt"
  },
  {
    "question": "ellos viven",
    "answer": "sie leben"
  },
  {
    "question": "usted vive",
    "answer": "Sie leben"
  },
  {
    "question": "el padre",
    "answer": "der Vater"
  },
  {
    "question": "la madre",
    "answer": "die Mutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "los padres",
    "answer": "die Eltern"
  },
  {
    "question": "el hermano",
    "answer": "der Bruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "la hermana",
    "answer": "die Schwester"
  },
  {
    "question": "el hijo",
    "answer": "der Sohn"
  },
  {
    "question": "la hija",
    "answer": "die Tochter"
  },
  {
    "question": "el abuelo",
    "answer": "der Großvater"
  },
  {
    "question": "la abuela",
    "answer": "die Großmutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "los abuelos",
    "answer": "die Großeltern"
  },
  {
    "question": "el tío",
    "answer": "der Onkel"
  },
  {
    "question": "la tía",
    "answer": "die Tante"
  },
  {
    "question": "el esposo / el marido",
    "answer": "der Mann"
  },
  {
    "question": "la esposa / la mujer",
    "answer": "die Frau"
  },
  {
    "question": "el novio",
    "answer": "der Freund"
  },
  {
    "question": "la novia",
    "answer": "die Freundin"
  }
]